Michael Jackson's Thriller is a horror, thriller,
music film directed by John Landis.
A night at the movies turns terrifying when Michael
and his date are attacked by zombies.
Released at the height of Thriller’s success, the short film redefined the music
video, broke racial barriers, and became the first inducted into the U.S.
National Film Registry.
Michael Jackson, played by Michael Jackson.
Michael's Girlfriend, played by Ola Ray.
Narrator (voice), played by Vincent Price.
Zombie (uncredited), played by Cynthia Garris.
Zombie (uncredited), played by Mick Garris.
Dancer (uncredited), played by Hanala Sagal.
Michael Jackson's Thriller is the music video for the song "Thriller" by the
American singer Michael Jackson, released on December 2, 1983.
It was directed by John Landis, written by Jackson and
Landis, and stars Jackson and Ola Ray.
It references numerous horror films and has Jackson
dancing with a horde of zombies.
Jackson's sixth album, Thriller, was released in November 1982 and spent months at the top of the
Billboard 200, backed by successful videos for the singles "Billie Jean" and "Beat It".
In July 1983, after Thriller was displaced from the top of the chart,
Jackson and his team decided to release "Thriller" as a single.
Jackson hired Landis to direct the video after seeing his
1981 film An American Werewolf in London.
It was filmed at various locations in Los Angeles, including the Palace
Theater, with a budget much larger than previous music videos.
A making-of documentary, Making Michael Jackson's Thriller,
was produced to sell to television networks.
Michael Jackson's Thriller was launched to great
anticipation and played regularly on MTV.
It doubled sales of Thriller, helping it become the best-selling album in history, and the
documentary sold over a million copies, becoming the best-selling VHS tape at the time.
It is credited for transforming music videos into a serious art form, breaking down racial barriers in popular
entertainment, popularizing the making-of documentary format, and driving home video sales.
The success made Jackson a dominant force in global pop culture.
Many elements of Michael Jackson's Thriller have had a lasting impact on popular culture, such as the
zombie dance and Jackson's red jacket, designed by Landis's wife, Deborah Nadoolman.
The video is closely associated with Halloween, and
fans worldwide re-enact its zombie dance.
The Library of Congress described it as the most famous music video of all time, and it has
been named the greatest video by various publications and readers' polls.
In 2009, Michael Jackson's Thriller became the first music video inducted into the US National Film
Registry by the Library of Congress as "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
It reached one billion views on YouTube in 2024.
The film explores themes of dancing, date, narration, music video, zombie.
The tone is dark and intense.